"行尸走肉"前情提要
Previously on AMC's The Walking Dead...
欢迎来到Woodbury
Welcome to Woodbury.
我们是一个社区
We're a community.
那是我妻子 我女儿和我本人
Well, that's my wife, that's my daughter and me.
别伤害我女儿
Don't hurt my little girl.
把Michonne交给我
I want Michonne.
把她交给我 旧账就不算了
Turn her over and all this goes away.
他想强占监狱 想置我们于死地
He wants the prison. He wants us dead.
我们该去追杀他们
We should go after them.
把他斩草除根
We should finish him.
你干什么!?
What the hell are you doing!?
- 这不值得  - 那是大屠杀
- It's not worth it.  - That was a slaughter.
我已经漂泊了好几个月了
I've been on the road for a couple of months.
你自己?
By yourself?
是啊
Yeah.
你之前住哪儿啊?
Where did you live before that?
一个小镇上
I was in a town.
那儿有行尸吗?
Were the monsters there?
没有
No.
很安全
It was safe.
大家都很友善
Full of good people.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
他失控了
He just lost it.
谁?
Who?
镇上的负责人
The man in charge.
我差点没活着出来
I barely got out alive.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影纸 时间轴: 桃茜茜
翻译: 落寞卷菜 欣欣然
校对: 潇妹纸
行尸走肉 第四季 第六集
你看起来快不行了
You look like you barely got out alive.
- Tara  - 我的意思是...
- Tara.  - I mean...
我们神经绷得太紧了
We're a little on edge.
我们一直困在这里 等国民警卫队救援...
We've been holed up in here waiting for the National Guard since...
- 自灾难临头以来  - 怎么说话呢
- The shit hit the fan.  - Language.
自他妈的灾难临头以来
Since the crap hit the fan.
可是国民警卫队
Which it did
却抛弃了我们
right before it got flung all over the damn place.
你打算待在这里吗?
Are you planning on staying in the building?
到底要不要留下?
Are you planning on staying or not?
- 该死的 你是哑巴啊   - Tara
- Holy shit, with the no talking.  - Tara.
我姐姐在问你话
My sister asked you a question.
只呆一晚
Just for the night.
看见了吗?
You see this?
这是一把装满子弹的标配史密斯&维森手枪
This here is a fully loaded, standard issue Smith & Wesson.
我是一名亚特兰大市警察
I'm Atlanta City Police
我的武器足够在接下来的十年里
and I have enough artillery in here to kill you
每天杀你一次
every day for the next 10 years.
你要是敢胡来
You mess with me or my family,
我发誓 我会杀了你
and I swear to Christ, I will put you down.
明白?
Got it?
明白
Got it.
那就没事了
Then we're cool.
碰碰拳头
Pound it.
给你
Here, bro.
我们会替你保管着 直到你离开
We'll hold onto this until you go.
对
Yeah.
你叫什么?
You got a name?
我叫Brian
Brian.
叫Brian Heriot
Brian Heriot.
你一定饿了吧
You got to be hungry.
找不到别的食物了
You're not gonna find anything better in there.
Tara把房间都翻了个底朝天了
Tara ransacked the place
Wilhelm小姐也动身去佛罗里达了
after Miss Wilhelm took off for Florida.
Wilhelm小姐很喜欢吃棉豆
Big fan of butter beans, Miss Wilhelm.
谢谢
Thank you.
四 五
four, five.
快点 小不点 让我看看你有什么本事
Come on, kiddo. Show me what you got here.
一切都好吗?
Everything okay?
她又没吃饭
She didn't eat again.
她喜欢腌牛肉 试试那个
She likes the corned beef. Try that.
最后两罐是为爸爸留的
I'm saving the last two cans for Dad.
她不是挑剔 只是太害怕了
She's not picky, she's terrified.
嘘
Shh.
别乱动
Why don't you slow down, buddy, all right?
这里可不是假日酒店
This ain't the Holiday Inn.
左边的水桶是用来洗漱的
Bucket on the left is for washing,
右边是洗涤用的
right is for rinsing.
Tara啊
Tara.
哦
Oh.
对不起
Sorry.
吃饱了吗?
You get enough to eat?
我给你泡杯咖啡
I'll get you some coffee.
坐吧
Sit down.
坐那儿 去吧
Right there. Go on.
该你了 走吧
Go ahead, roll again.
嘿 伙计
Hey, come here.
有烟吗?
You got a cigarette?
爸爸 你的氧气罐
Dad, your oxygen tank.
看不见红色标签上写的什么?
Do you not see that red sticker?
如果因为一支烟炸了这个房间 我会遭天谴的
I'll be damned if a Merit Ultra Menthol is gonna blow this place up
毕竟千辛万苦都是为了活下去 对吗?
after all the work we've done to stay alive up here. Okay?
都一样的 Lily
It's all the same, Lily.
你能不唠叨吗
You can stop that talk right there.
只不过一支烟罢了
It's just a cigarette.
自便
Help yourself.
我们吃巧克力棒好几天了
We got roni sticks for days.
或许都好几年了
Years, probably.
看见那辆停在外面的卡车了吗?
You see that big truck parked outside?
拜托 伙计 那辆可爱的食品卡车
Come on, dude, the Gorbelli food truck.
Ray Charles本来能发现的
Ray Charles could have seen it.
是啊
Yeah.
爸爸给他们开车
Dad drove for them.
有时候还戴着氧气瓶呢
Even with the tank.
人们关了75号公路那天...
The day they closed down the 75...
就是大难临头那天
When the S-H-I-T hit the fan.
他去学校接了Megan 又从医院接了我...
He grabbed Megan from school, picked me up at the hospital...
她从垃圾堆里淘出了好多氧气罐
She stole a bunch of oxygen tanks from that dump.
然后我们三个人就冲过去找Tara
Then the three of us rushed over to get Tara.
当时我正在局里上班
I was at the station working, booking.
当一切发生的时候
With everything going on,
僵尸入侵攻击 军队攻入亚特兰大
the attacks, the Army going into Atlanta,
他坚决不允许大家离开他的视线
he wasn't about to let us out of his sight.
我们很幸运 那个老男人的卡车
Lucky for us, the old man's truck was pretty much stocked
从上到下
floor to ceiling with sketti rings,
被各种零食小吃几乎塞满了
turkey chili, and these little suckers.
Meg 爷爷休息下 行吗?
Meg, Granddad needs a break, okay?
- Lily  - 没问题 爸爸
- Lily.  - Sure, Daddy.
我数到三
On three.
过来搭把手啊 大块头
A little help here, big guy.
这里
Here.
哦 对 不 不是说你
Oh, right. No, not you.
这屋里的另一个人
The other big guy in the room.
Tara啊
Tara.
好的
Okay.
我数三声
On three.
好了 一 二...
Okay, one, two...
这里 这里
Here. Here.
嘿 你听见了吗?
Hey. You hear them?
嗯
Yeah.
帮我抬下腿 伙计?
Get my legs, friend?
Tara上去过好几次
Tara's been up there a bunch of times
把那帮混蛋杀个片甲不留
blasting them bastards to pieces.
她说它们不断回来
She says they just keep getting back up.
我告诉她别再去杀了
I told her no more.
别再浪费她的弹药
Can't afford to waste her bullets.
你有孩子吗?
You got kids?
没有
No.
我女儿们出生的时候
When my girls were born,
我才真正懂得一个男人的职责
that's when I finally figured out what it was to be a man.
你懂的 一个真正的男人
You know, a real man.
你要保护她们 保证她们的安全
You protect them, you keep them safe.
你要让她们更坚强
You just try to make them stronger
直到她们有能力自己去闯荡
until they can look out for themselves.
但是在这儿
But this here,
我... 我从来都没指望
I... I never counted on this.
嘿 我有个伙计
Hey, I got a buddy.
Bill Jenkins 他住在楼上的303
Bill Jenkins, he lives up in 303.
他有一套超级酷的西洋双陆棋
He's got a real nice backgammon set up there.
他却不稀罕 把它扔在床低下
He won't mind and he keeps it under his bed there.
只是... 拜托
Just... please.
你熟悉外面的环境
You've been out there in the world
你知道怎么保护自己
and you know how to handle yourself around those things.
听着 我知道你或许不明白
Look, I know you might not understand it
因为你没有女儿
cause you don't got a baby girl of your own,
但是...
but...
那套双陆棋或许能让我的Megan张口说话
it might be something that might make my Megan talk again.
拜托了
Please.
谢谢
Thank you.
客气了
You're welcome.
一些路上或许能用到的东西
Couple things for the road.
我不需要
I'm okay.
你帮助了我们
You helped us.
我们得感谢你
We're saying thank you.
你就接受吧
Deal with it.
我想你需要这把枪
I guess you'll be needing this back.
你留着吧
Keep it.
别...
Don't...
扔给我
throw that at me.
这是你的枪 拿回去吧
It's your gun. You can have it back.
你需要一只
You need another one.
我有这个
I have this.
Tara说得对
Tara was right.
我们该搜你的身
We should have frisked you.
我从楼上找到的
I found it upstairs.
你留着那把
You keep that.
一定要击中脑袋
You have to kill the brain.
什么?
What?
你妹妹 她总是打四肢
Your sister, she shot 'em in the body,
但是只有击中脑袋
but you have to hit 'em here.
才能杀死他们
That's what kills them.
为什么?
Why?
我得问你件事
I need to ask you something.
我爸爸肺癌肺癌晚期
My dad's got stage four lung cancer.
我学过几年肿瘤学
I worked oncology for a few years.
他已经到了弥留之际了
He's nearing the end.
但是只有两天的氧气量了
He's got about two days of oxygen.
或许都不到两天
Maybe less.
我们都没想到他能撑这么久
We never thought he'd make it this long.
你已经为我们做了这么多 但是...
You've already done so much for us, but...
离这里几个街区
there's an old folks home
有一个老朋友的家里
a couple of blocks from here.
只要一罐就够了
Even one tank would mean everything.
他是唯一能让Megan露出笑容的人
He's the only one who can put a smile on Megan's face.
哪怕只是几秒钟
Even for a second.
- 都是没拆封的  - 你还好么?
- They're both full.  - Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
你都没给我机会说谢谢
You didn't let me say thank you.
嗯 我没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
坐下来
Sit.
让我重拾旧业吧
Let me be a nurse again.
好消息是伤口看起来不用缝合
Good news is it doesn't look like you need any stitches.
坏消息是...
Bad news...
会像被凶狠的蜜蜂蜇了一样疼
this is gonna sting like a couple of angry bees.
有事可做的感觉真好
Feels good to have something to do.
没人提到过世界末日有多无聊
Nobody ever mentioned just how boring the end of the world was gonna be.
她以为你是她爸爸
She thought you were her dad.
Megan以为
Megan.
就在她看见你在马路上时
When she saw you out there on the street.
三年半前的一晚
He went out one night about three and a half years ago
他出门去买啤酒和彩票
to get a couple beers and a Powerball ticket.
说是马上就回来
Said he'd be right back.
Megan以为你是他爸爸
Megan thought you were him,
终于回家了
finally coming right back.
- 妈妈  - 我在屋里 宝贝
- Mama.  - In here, honey.
没事的 宝贝
Everything's okay, sweetheart.
Brian有个小伤口需要清洗消毒
Brian just got a boo-boo that needs a little cleaning up.
就像你碰伤时一样
Same as when you get a cut.
没有药膏了
I don't have the ointment.
在我回来前替我照看下病人好吗?
Why don't you watch my patient until I get back?
好的
Okay.
你眼睛怎么了?
What happened to your eye?
没了
It's gone.
是意外事故
Something happen to you
还是你天生就这样?
or were you just born like that?
是意外事故
Something happened to me.
这样问会不会不好?
Was that bad to ask?
没关系
No.
我可以告诉你我眼睛是怎么弄的
I'll tell you what happened to my eye,
但你要保证将它保密
but you have to promise to keep it secret.
我保证
I promise.
这是什么意思?
What's that?
拉钩钩啊
Pinkie swear.
外加发毒誓 泄密就会死掉
Plus cross my heart and hope to die.
那好...
Well...
我是个海盗
I'm a pirate.
不可能
No way.
呀 被你识破了
Yeah, you caught me.
真正的原因是在我帮助别人时发生了意外
What really happened was I was trying to help someone.
一个我非常爱的人
Someone I loved very much.
你是怎么帮他们的?
How were you trying to help them?
我是在保护他们 知道吗?
I was trying to protect them, you know?
让他们免受伤害
Stop them getting hurt.
但你自己却受伤了
But you got hurt instead.
是啊
Yeah.
他们也受伤了吗?
Did they get hurt, too?
呃...
Uh...
是啊 他们也受伤了
Yeah, yeah, they did.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我也觉得
Me, too.
这是什么
What is it?
象棋
Chess.
看起来真难
Looks hard.
对有些人来说可能很难 但你很聪明
Well, maybe for some folks, but you're smart.
很快就能学会
You'll catch on quick.
这个叫什么?
What's this one called?
卒
That's a pawn.
他们是你的士兵
They're your soldiers.
他们会死吗?
Do they die?
有时候会
Sometimes.
他们死掉你就会输吗?
Do you lose if they die?
不 不一定
No, not necessarily.
你可以牺牲很多士兵
You can lose a lot of soldiers,
但仍能赢得比赛
but still win the game.
这是国王
That's the king.
是你要抓住的人
That's the guy you want to capture.
- 你在干什么?  - 马上就知道了
- What are you doing?  - You'll see.
这样很像你
Looks like you.
是啊
Yeah.
来 咱们开玩吧
Come on, let's play.
白色是你的棋
So these ones are pawns.
(Gorbelli食品公司)
他死了
He's gone.
他死了有一会儿了
I think he's been gone a while.
你们都应该马上出去
Y'all should go now.
再给我们点时间
Just give us a minute.
我爱你 爸爸
I love you, Daddy.
Tara啊!
Tara!
- 住手! 你在干什么?  - 那已经不是爸爸了!
- Stop! What are you doing?  - It's not Dad!
- 住手!  - 那不是爸爸了!
- Stop!  - It's not Dad!
我是知道的
I know, okay?
不管怎样都会变成行尸吗?
It happens no matter what?
是的
Yeah.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
他可能会抓住我
He could have got me.
他差点就咬到我
He almost got me.
我在想
I was thinking
他会感激你的
he would have been grateful or whatever
是你阻止了他的袭击...
that you stopped him, from him...
你明白我的意思吧?
You know what I mean?
所以 我不跟你计较了
So, yeah, we're cool.
我走了
Good-bye.
不
No.
- 我们跟你走  - 不行
- We're coming with you.  - No.
必须要找个更安全的地方
There has to be someplace better,
你来帮我们找
and you're gonna help us find it.
- Lily  - 我看到照片了 Brian
- Lily.  - I saw the picture, Brian.
我知道你有过家庭
You had a family, I know that.
虽然我们不是你的家人
And I know we're not them.
但现在 我们就是你的家庭负担
But for now, you're stuck with us.
- 以后也将是这样  - 我做不到
- And that's just the way it's gonna be.  - I can't.
你已经在做了
You already have.
我们要往哪走?
Where should we go?
做计划也没用
No use making a plan.
要看他们能让我们去哪
We'll go where they let us.
他们是谁?
Who's they?
公路
The roads.
还有行尸
The biters.
我不算是个警察
I'm not really a cop.
也不完全是假的
I mean, it's not a total lie.
我进过警官学院
I was in the Academy.
抱歉对你说谎了
I'm sorry I lied to you.
无需抱歉
You don't have to be sorry.
还是很抱歉
Well, I am.
你觉得我们能找到地方吗?
Do you think we can make it?
我们会找到的
We'll make it.
你在说谎吗?
Are you lying to me?
没有
No.
到我们这里来啊 Megan
You can come join us, Megan.
她还需要时间去接受
It's just gonna take some time.
没关系的
It's okay.
很快就会找到其他的车
We'll find another car soon.
但愿你说的对
I hope you're right.
这些场面让我想起Sam
This whole country backdrop is reminding me of Sam.
- 又来了  - 我还以为她就是我的另一半
- Here we go.  - I thought she was the one.
你们只是一起去露营 吃蘑菇 仅此而已
Then you went camping, ate mushrooms, game over.
你忘记Sam崩溃掉 告诉我她有男朋友
You're forgetting the part where Sam broke down and told me she had a boyfriend,
她对女人不感兴趣
that she wasn't really into chicks.
啊 真是这辈子最烂的周末
Ugh, worst weekend of my life.
Tara小心
Tara.
哦 天啊 该死!
Oh, man. Damn it!
- 你还好吗?  - 我没事
- You all right?  - I'm fine.
- Tara 等下 让我看看  - 我没事!
- Tara, stop. Let me look at it.  - I'm fine!
把背包给我 我很好 没事的
Just hand me my backpack. I'm fine. I'm fine.
- 你能走吗?  - 能 我好着呢
- Can you walk?  - Yeah, I'm fine.
我没事 咱们走吧
I'm fine. Let's go.
扔掉你们的包 这边走 快走
Drop your bags. Let's go. Come on.
- Megan  - Megan 过来
- Megan.  - Megan, come on.
Megan 快点 过来
Megan, right now.  Come on.
- Megan!  - 快来啊 Megan
- Megan!  - Come on, Megan.
Megan 快过来
Megan, come on.
Megan 快点 过来啊
Megan, right now. Come on.
过来 Megan 来这边
Come on, Megan. Come on.
Megan快走!
Megan!
来吧
Here.
我们走
Come on.
走
Go.
快走
Move.
- Brian啊!  - 我在这呢
- Brian!  - I'm here.
对不起 你还好吗?
I'm sorry. You okay?
你还好吗?
You all right?
我绝对不会让你出事的
I'm never gonna let anything happen to you.
好吗?
Okay?
- 你发誓?  - 我发誓
- Promise?  - Cross my heart.
该死
Holy shit.
我发誓
Cross my heart.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影纸 时间轴: 桃茜茜
翻译: 落寞卷菜 欣欣然
校对: 潇妹纸